{"tossups": [{"question": "This person was released from Castle Thunder in an 1864 prisoner exchange. While working as a field surgeon, this doctor met Frances Hook, a female Union soldier disguised as a man. In 1907, this American published \"Crowning Constitutional Argument,\" claiming the U.S. Constitution already prescribed women's suffrage. This woman was arrested as a spy in New Orleans after helping a Confederate doctor with an amputation. For ten points, name this woman whose Medal of Honor was posthumously restored by Jimmy Carter.", "answer": "Mary Edwards <b><u>Walker</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One side in this battle threw off their armor as they were fleeing, leading to heightened casualties in the Bloody Meadow. Lord Fauconberg\u2019s archers benefited from the heavily one-sided winds at this battle, which was fought during a snowstorm on Palm Sunday. This battle led to the deaths of Andrew Trollope [[TRAH-lup]] and the Earl of Northumberland. An estimated 50,000 soldiers fought at this battle, often considered the bloodiest battle fought in England. For ten points, name this 1461 Yorkist victory during the Wars of the Roses in which Edward IV deposed Henry VI.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Towton</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Henry Hester served as the long-term secretary of this building, to which he introduced the practice of trading futures. Originally built at the intersection of Gravier [[GRAH-vyer]] and Carondelet [[kah-ron-deh-LET]] Streets, this location aimed to create a more seller-friendly counterpart to a similar one in New York. An Edgar Degas [[deh-GAH]] painting sometimes erroneously titled for this location depicts the raw variety of its central good as well as stacks of bales. For ten points, name this building which facilitated the trade of a major Southern good, found in a Louisiana city.", "answer": "<b><u>New Orleans Cotton Exchange</u></b> Building (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One of these object\u2019s named after the German city of Mainz [[MAINTS]] depicts Augustus flanked by two gods as Tiberius presents him a statue commemorating his victory. This object was largely replaced in combat when the <em>spatha</em> became more popular. After the reforms of Gaius Marius, this weapon was, in addition to the <em>pugio</em>, <em>pila</em>, and <em>scutum</em>, standardized for legionnaires. <em>Capulus</em> was the term for the hilt of these objects which allowed shielded infantry to fight with forward jabs. For ten points, name this short Roman sword.", "answer": "<b><u>Gladius</u></b> (prompt on answers including \"sword\")", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "Before the Civil War, this general was court-martialed for attacking an enlisted man with the flat of his sword. This man succeeded William Tecumseh Sherman as the leader of the Army of Ohio, and during the Confederate Heartland Offensive, the Army of Mississippi inflicted large casualties on this man's troops in Kentucky. Union forces at the Battle of Perryville were commanded by this man, three of whose divisions assisted Ulysses S. Grant at the Battle of Shiloh. For ten points, name this Union general with Spanish-sounding given names.", "answer": "Don Carlos <b><u>Buell</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 2009, a collection of this writer's papers were purchased by the University of Cambridge, including letters from the Western Front and Palestine, as well as a draft of \"A Soldier's Dedication.\" This writer fictionalized himself as George Sherston, whose innocence is described in <em>Memoirs of a Fox-Hunting Man</em>. A failed counter-attack is the title subject of one poem by this man, who became acquainted with a fellow poet while staying at a military hospital suffering from shell shock. For ten points, name this leading World War One poet who influenced his friend, Wilfred Owen.", "answer": "Siegfried <b><u>Sassoon</u></b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "Bernardino Verro served as the first mayor of this city in which he promoted \u201ccollective renting\u201d among agricultural workers. The name of this city may have been inspired by a warrior with the same nickname as Richard I of England. A man born in this city named Salvatore Riina was known as <em>il capo dei capi</em> or \u201cthe boss of bosses.\u201d This city inspired a fictional family created by Mario Puzo. For ten points, name this Sicilian city which inspired the surname of the central family in <em>The Godfather</em>.", "answer": "<b><u>Corleone</u></b> (or <b><u>Curliuni</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The HMS <em>York</em> was employed by Lumley Leyster at this battle, during which the HMS <em>Illustrious</em> launched 21 Fairey Swordfish. The Japanese forces that conducted Pearl Harbor may have studied this battle, because it targeted a shallow harbor. Inigo Campioni\u2019s [[kahm-PYOH-nees]] fleet was attacked by Andrew Cunningham's forces in this battle, which featured wide use of torpedo bombers. For ten points, name this 1940 naval battle, fought around an Italian harbor.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Taranto</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "After launching the Louisbourg expedition, this man used a massive payment in gold and silver from the U.K. to end the use of paper currency. This man bequeathed money to build Holden Chapel and served as lieutenant governor to Thomas Pownall. This man traveled with Jonathan Belcher to negotiate with the Abenaki and married Pelef Sanford's granddaughter, Margaret, securing an alliance with Andrew Oliver. Francis Bernard appointed this man to the governorship he held during the Boston Massacre. For ten points, name this colonial governor of Massachusetts.", "answer": "Thomas <b><u>Hutchinson</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "An 1834 treaty signed in this country acknowledged one of its freedom fighters as the governor of Mascara [[mah-SKAH-rah]]. A leader of this country nicknamed the \"modern Jugurtha\" [[yoo-GUR-thah]] participated in the Regha\u00efa [[reh-KHAI-ee-uh]] attack and was named Emir Abdelkader. The conquest of Biskra occurred in this country, where many Europeans who migrated to cities like Constantine and Oran came to be called <em>pied-noirs</em> [[pyehd-NWAHR]]. Forces under Charles X and Louis Philippe I defeated the <em>dey</em> of, for ten points, what North African country?", "answer": "People's Democratic Republic of <b><u>Algeria</u></b> (or <b><u>al-Dzayir</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "The leader of this organization was told that it was not possible for it to accomplish \u201cone-tenth of the expectations\u201d placed upon it. A number of AME churches were established by this group, whose agents also helped establish hospitals and provide education under the oversight of Oliver O. Howard. Described as \u201cfacing Hercules\u2019s task\u201d by William Tecumseh Sherman, this organization promised plots of forty acres from confiscated land to its namesake group. For ten points, name this Reconstruction-era government agency.", "answer": "<b><u>Freedmen</u></b>'s <b><u>Bureau[a] (or [a]Bureau</u></b> of Refugees, <b><u>Freedmen</u></b>, and Abandoned Lands)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A major victory for this monarch was secured at a battle during which Henrik Parow died. This monarch chose the feast day of a namesake saint from Antioch as the date to sign one agreement. The nickname \u201cKing Breechless\u201d was derisively given to this monarch by one opponent, Albert of Mecklenburg. Due to the death of Olaf II, this monarch was succeeded by a grandnephew named Eric of Pomerania. A treaty calling for \u201charmony and love\u201d between three realms was secured by this monarch to create the Kalmar Union. For ten points, name this Danish queen who united Scandinavia.", "answer": "<b><u>Margaret I</u></b> of Denmark (accept <b><u>Margrete</u></b> Valdemarsdatter)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The Battle of Kunyang was a defeat for this dynasty at the hands of a member of the Liu family. After the execution of her son, Mother L\u00fc took up arms as part of a movement during this dynasty led by Fan Chong known as the Red Eyebrows Rebellion. Emperor Guangwu took power at the end of this dynasty. Ruling from 9 to 23 CE, this dynasty's leader aimed to implement the policies of the Chinese classics. For ten points, name this short-lived dynasty which interrupted the Han.", "answer": "<b><u>Xin</u></b> [[SHIN]] Dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This opera premiered during the Carnival season, several decades after its composer completed <em>The Combat of Tancred and Clorinda</em>. In one scene, Ottone [[oh-TOH-neh]] claims that while the title figure is in his heart, \u201cDrusilla is on [his] lips.\" Considered the first opera to deal with historical figures, the characters in this work include Seneca and a noblewoman who becomes a Roman empress. For ten points, name this opera about the crowning of the mistress of Nero, composed by Claudio Monteverdi.", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>Coronation of Poppea</u></b></em> (accept <em>L'<b><u>incoronazione di Poppea</u></b></em>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {}, {"question": "In response to this event, Calvin Coolidge signed an act authorizing new Army Corps of Engineers projects. Herbert Hoover oversaw the construction of the world's largest system of levees following this event. This event spawned a series of refugee camps known for their extreme racial inequality, inspiring musical pieces including \"Backwater Blues\" and \"High Water Everywhere.\" For ten points, name this event, sometimes called the \u201cHigh Water of 1927,\" the worst event of its kind in U.S. history.", "answer": "Great <b><u>Mississippi Flood</u></b> of 1927", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "John Ladue founded this city in which a large fire started at its Bodega Hotel. Forty Mile was found near this city, which was home to Diamond Tooth Gertie's Gambling Hall, its country\u2019s oldest casino. Many inhabitants left this city after a discovery in Nome. Prior to that, numerous boom towns were set up along routes to this city which was described in Jack London\u2019s <em>The Call of the Wild</em>. Mounties policed this city during an 1896-1899 period that brought many people to the Yukon. For ten points, name this center of the Klondike Gold Rush.", "answer": "<b><u>Dawson</u></b> City", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "This work notes that \"the humblest citizen...when clad in the armor of a righteous cause, is stronger than all the hosts of error\" and evokes the Civil War by noting that \"brother has been arrayed against brother.\" This speech notes that national independence is \"the issue of 1776 over again\" and urges the Democrats to fight for \"the struggling masses.\" This speech ends by pleading not to \"press down upon the brow of labor this crown of thorns.\" For ten points, name this pro-\"Free Silver\" speech given in 1896 by William Jennings Bryan.", "answer": "<b><u>Cross of Gold</u></b> speech", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Prior to this battle, the last of the Akechi clan died at the hands of a loyal officer in Hosokawa territory. This battle, which occurred after the untimely death of skilled diplomat Maeda Toshiie [[mah-EH-dah toh-SHEE-ee-eh]], involved the betrayal of Mori Terumoto from the Western Army while in Osaka Castle. This battle effectively ended the Sengoku, or Warring States period. For ten points, name this 1600 battle in which Tokugawa Ieyasu [[ee-eh-YAH-soo]] defeated the Toyotomi clan, paving the way for him to establish his namesake shogunate.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Sekigahara</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This author controversially compared the JFK assassination to a \u201cDownhill Motor Race.\u201d This author of <em>The Atrocity Exhibition</em> wrote about a march to Nantao, in which the protagonist avoids starving to death after Allied bombers drop food supplies. Jim Graham is interned in Lunghua Civilian Assembly Centre in a novel inspired by this man\u2019s time growing up during the Japanese occupation of Shanghai. That novel by this man was adapted into a Steven Spielberg film starring child actor Christian Bale. For ten points, name this author of <em>Empire of the Sun</em> and <em>Crash</em>.", "answer": "J.G. <b><u>Ballard</u></b> (or James Graham <b><u>Ballard</u></b>)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "A man with this name was a son-in-law of Henry I of England and was known as the \u201cGreat Chief\u201d or \u201cCanmore.\" The aforementioned predecessor of Donald III was a king who served as the inspiration for a character of this name who approaches Dunsinane while another character visits Three Witches. That character of this name was inspired by <em>Holinshed's Chronicles</em> and is assisted by MacDuff in reclaiming his throne. A number of Scottish kings share their name with, for ten points, what son of Duncan who avenges his father's death at the hands of MacBeth?", "answer": "<b><u>Malcolm</u></b> (accept <b><u>Malcolm</u></b> III of Scotland)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Drama"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>In a hearing after this event, one man told Samuel Untermyer that commercial</u></b> <b><u>credit was primarily based on character. This event was precipitated by a failed</u></b> <b><u>attempt by the Heinze brothers and Charles Morse to (+)</u> corner a market of stocks belonging to the United Copper Company. The Knickerbocker Trust collapsed during this event, which prompted the passage of the Aldrich-Vreeland Act. A bank bail-out during this event led to the (*) </b>creation of the Federal Reserve. For ten points, name this early twentieth-century financial crisis.", "answer": "<b><u>Panic</u></b> of <b><u>1907</u></b> (accept <b><u>1907</u></b> Bankers' <b><u>Panic</u></b>; accept <b><u>Knickerbocker Crisis</u> </b>before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The third of this text\u2019s twelve books covers a civil war between the sons of</u></b> <b><u>Dunvallo. Gildas is among the historians cited by the author of this text, which</u></b> <b><u>chronicles Cassivellaunus\u2019s [[kah-sih-veh-LAW-nuh-sus]] refusal to pay tribute to</u></b> <b><u>Caesar. Aurelius Ambrosius\u2019s defeat of (+)</u> Vortigern is chronicled in the eighth book of this text, which includes the earliest known appearance of the story of King Lear. Brutus\u2019s renaming of the central location opens this work, which ends with the rise of the (*) </b>Anglo-Saxons to power. For ten points, name this pseudohistorical 1136 book by Geoffrey of Monmouth.", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>History of the Kings of Britain</u></b></em> (accept <em><b><u>Historia regum Britanniae</u></b></em> or <em><b><u>De</u></b></em> <em><b><u>gestis Britonum</u></b></em>)", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this conflict, Usman and Harun Thohir bombed the MacDonald House.</u></b> <b><u>The Battle of Long Jawai was one of the earliest battles in this conflict, during which</u></b> <b><u>British forces were sent to Kalimantan [[kah-lee-MAHN-tahn]] to prevent strategic</u></b> <b><u>attacks by one side in Operation (+)</u> Claret [[KLARE-et]]. In this conflict, a revolt was put down in Brunei [[broo-NAI]] against the formation of a greater political entity. The jungle terrain of (*) </b>Borneo made it difficult for both sides to navigate, for ten points, what conflict stemming from Indonesia's opposition to the formation of Malaysia?", "answer": "<b><u>Konfrontasi</u></b> (accept <b><u>Indonesia-Malaysia Confrontation</u></b> before mentioned; accept <b><u>Borneo Confrontation</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This body includes the House of Keys, who elected Juan Watterson as Speaker</u></b> <b><u>in 2016. This body's namesake hill is also called the Hill of the Church of John and</u></b> <b><u>contains several circular platforms which were used for the inaugurations of William</u></b> <b><u>(+)</u> le Scripe and John Stanley. This body is located in Douglas, and its name is derived from an Old Norse word for (*) </b>\"assembly,\" similar to such a body in Iceland. For ten points, name this \"oldest continuous parliament,\" whose \"deemsters\" read out brief summaries of laws in Manx.", "answer": "High Court of <b><u>Tynwald</u></b> (prompt on \"Parliament of the Isle of Man\" or \"Manx Parliament\")", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b><u>Following this event, Ichabod Northup and James Jefferson pushed for</u></b> <b><u>expanding suffrage to African Americans. This event included a meeting at Acotes</u></b> <b><u>[[ah-KOH-tehs]] Hill. Members of this rebellion were attacked by the Algerine Law</u></b> <b><u>and opposed by the (*)</u> Law and Order Party. This rebellion led to the case </b><em><b>Luther v. </b><b>Border</b></em><b>, and Samuel Ward King was elected as governor in this event, which involved men from Bernon Mill Village opposing the (*) </b>Charterites. For ten points, name this 1841 to 1842 rebellion which sought to achieve universal white male suffrage in Rhode Island.", "answer": "<b><u>Dorr</u></b>'s Rebellion (accept <b><u>Dorr</u></b>'s War; accept synonyms for \"Rebellion\" such as \"Revolt\" or \"Uprising\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The Newcastle March appears in the third act of this opera which precedes a</u></b> <b><u>work in a series that features a \u201cHymn to the Sun.\" This second opera in the</u> </b><em><b><u>Portrait</u></b></em> <em><b><u>Trilogy</u></b></em><b><u> has three acts focusing on different historical figures including Leo Tolstoy</u></b> <b><u>and (+)</u> Martin Luther King, Jr. References to \u201cthe Kuru Field of Justice\u201d and Rabindranath Tagore [[rah-BIN-drah-nath TAY-gohr]] appear in this work titled for a (*) </b>concept that translates to \u201ctruth\u201d in its namesake language. For ten points, name this Philip Glass opera based on the life of Mahatma Gandhi.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Satyagraha</u></b></em>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man created the</u> </b><em><b><u>Celibano</u></b></em><b><u> faction, and after this man flew to the Century</u></b> <b><u>of Progress in Chicago, a monument on the Lakefront Trail was dedicated to him and</u></b> <b><u>his transatlantic flights. This governor of (+)</u> Libya, who constructed a namesake coastal highway, may have received intelligence from the Hungarian aristocrat L\u00e1szl\u00f3 Alm\u00e1sy [[LAH-zloh al-MAH-see]]. (*) </b>For ten points, name this Italian Fascist, an \"heir apparent\" to Benito Mussolini, who led the Italian Royal Air Force before his plane was shot down by friendly fire.", "answer": "Italo <b><u>Balbo</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>William Eaton reported that this man helped to jail Davis Hatch, and William</u></b> <b><u>Cazneau and this man created plans to annex Santo Domingo. This man, who used the</u></b> <b><u>code name \"Sylph,\" was tried by Asa Bird Gardiner. While rowing from the</u> </b><em><b><u>Pharos</u></b></em><b><u>,</u></b> <b><u>this engineer of the (+)</u> Mosquito Inlet Lighthouse drowned. Indicted in the Safe Burglary Conspiracy, this man purchased land in Florida using money he was gifted by John McDonald. Edwards Pierrepoint [[PEER-pahnt]] and Benjamin Bristow prosecuted this (*) </b>Whiskey Ring member. For ten points, name this private secretary to Ulysses Grant.", "answer": "Orville E(lias) <b><u>Babcock</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A 1329 treaty signed in this city involved the Wittelsbach [[VIT-ells-bahk]]</u></b> <b><u>Emperor Louis IV agreeing to split Bavaria. Richard de la Pole was killed during a</u></b> <b><u>battle named for this city, in which the victorious forces were led by Charles (+)</u> de Lannoy. That battle in this city was largely fought in Visconti [[vis-KAHN-tee]] Park and brought about the Treaty of Madrid. Francis I was captured in this city, which was for a time the capital of (*) </b>Lombardy. The decisive battle of the Italian Wars of the 1520s occurred in, for ten points, what city to the south of Milan?", "answer": "<b><u>Pavia</u></b> (accept <b><u>Ticinum</u></b>; or <b><u>Papia</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A trait known as \u201clarrikinism\u201d is often conflated with the \u201cspirit\u201d named for</u></b> <b><u>this military unit. An enlisted member of this unit named John Simpson spent over</u></b> <b><u>three and a half weeks conducting rescue operations aided by donkeys. William (+)</u></b> <b>Birdwood commanded this unit after serving during the Boer Wars on the staff of Herbert Kitchener. Formed in Egypt in 1914, this corps is best known for its engagements against the (*) </b>Ottoman Empire. For ten points, name this army corps known for its bravery at Gallipoli, comprised of soldiers from Australia and New Zealand.", "answer": "<b><u>ANZAC</u></b> (accept <b><u>Australian and New Zealand Army Corps</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This general repulsed a raid led by and named for John Hunt Morgan before</u></b> <b><u>going on to serve as the first president of the NRA. The slow speed at which his</u></b> <b><u>engineers built pontoon bridges over the (+)</u> Rappahannock River contributed to this man\u2019s defeat at an 1862 Virginia battle which earned him the nickname \u201cButcher of (*) </b>Fredericksburg.\u201d Though reluctant to succeed George McClellan, this man was compelled to do so out of dislike for the other candidate, Joseph Hooker. For ten points, name this Union general and governor of Rhode Island.", "answer": "Ambrose <b><u>Burnside</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}